Olive, the Other Reindeer is a animation, family,
comedy film directed by Steve Moore.
After mis-hearing a radio broadcast about Santa canceling his Christmas trip due to an injured
reindeer, Olive the dog decides to travel to the North Pole and volunteer to be a replacement.
Unfortunately, Olive must deal with an evil postman who's
tired of handling all the extra Christmas mail.
Will Martini the penguin be able to help Olive realize her dream?
Olive (voice), played by Drew Barrymore.
Santa Claus (voice), played by Ed Asner.
The Postman (voice), played by Dan Castellaneta.
Martini (voice), played by Joe Pantoliano.
Fido (voice), played by Peter MacNicol.
Arturo (voice), played by Matt Groening.
Olive, the Other Reindeer is a 1999 American animated Christmas comedy musical television special
written by Steve Young, based on the 1997 children's book by Vivian Walsh and J.
Otto Seibold, and directed by Academy Award-nominated
animator Steve Moore (credited as "Oscar Moore").
The feature was produced by Matt Groening's The Curiosity
Company and animated by DNA Productions.
Drew Barrymore voices the title character, and she is
credited as an executive producer on the special.
The special first aired on December 17, 1999, alongside Futurama on Fox, exactly ten
years after the premiere date of Groening's television series The Simpsons.
It was produced by Fox Television Studios and Flower Films.
During its initial broadcast, the special brought in 6.06 million
viewers, and an additional 5.22 million the following year.
After airing again the following year, the special made its first cable television premiere on Nickelodeon on December 15, 2001; It would then premiere the
following year on Cartoon Network on December 14, 2002, and aired during each holiday season until it was last seen on December 24, 2012.
The special would also air on other local syndicated networks,
such as The WB, MyNetworkTV, The CW and WGN-TV.
The story is based on the 1997 children's book by Vivian Walsh and J.
Otto Seibold and illustrated by J.
Otto Seibold.
In the song, "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer", the lyric "All of the other reindeer" can be misheard
in dialects with the cot–caught merger as the mondegreen "Olive, the other reindeer".
The special was nominated for the Emmy Award for Outstanding Animated Program.
The tone is lighthearted.